{
	"questions" : [
		{
			"question" : "Who invented the light bulb?",
			"difficult" : "Easy",
			"allAnswers" : [
				"Thomas Alva Edison",
        "Ion Creanga",
				"Michael Faraday"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "Thomas Alva Edison"
		},
		{
			"question" : "Who invented the light bulb?",
			"difficult" : "Medium",
			"allAnswers" : [
				"Michael Faraday",
				"Thomas Alva Edison",
				"Thomas Newcomen"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "Thomas Alva Edison"
		},
		{
			"question" : "Who invented the light bulb?",
			"difficult" : "Hard",
			"allAnswers" : [
				"Thomas Savery",
				"Thomas Alva Edison",
				"Thomas Newcomen"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "Thomas Alva Edison"
		},
		{
			"question" : "For what scientist has been invented the program called Equalizer to help him to communicate?",
			"difficult" : "Easy",
			"allAnswers" :[
				"Galileo Galilei",
				"Stephen Hawking",
				"George Eastman"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "Stephen Hawking"
		},
		{
            "question" : "In what year was invented the program called Equalizer that helped Stephen Hawking to communicate?",
			"difficult" : "Hard",
			"allAnswers" :[
				"1952",
				"1978",
				"1986"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "1986"
		},
		{
			"question" : "Which were the fields of research of Stephen Hawking?",
			"difficult" : "Medium",
			"allAnswers" :[
				"Quantum mechanics",
				"General relativity",
				"Quantum mechanics and general relativity"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "Quantum mechanics and general relativity"
		},
		{
			"question" : "Who is the creator of the formula E=mc^2?",
			"difficult" : "Easy",
			"allAnswers":[
				"Mihai Eminescu",
				"Albert Einstein",
				"Lee De Forest"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "Albert Einstein"
		},
		{
			"question" : "In what country was born Albert Einstein?",
			"difficult" : "Medium",
			"allAnswers":[
				"Germania",
				"Belgia",
				"Franța"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "Germania"
		},
		{
			"question" : "In what year died Albert Einstein?",
			"difficult" : "Hard",
			"allAnswers":[
				"1942",
				"1955",
				"1957"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "1955"
		},
		{
			"question" : "What was Isaac Newton?",
			"difficult" : "Easy",
			"allAnswers":[
				"mathematician",
				"physicist",
				"playwright"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "physicist"
		},
		{
			"question" : "Who established the three universal laws of motion?",
			"difficult" : "Medium",
			"allAnswers":[
				"Isaac Newton",
				"Galileo Galilei",
				"Albert Einstein"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "Isaac Newton"
		},
		{
			"question" : "At what age died the physicist Isaac Newton?",
			"difficult" : "Hard",
			"allAnswers":[
				"80 years",
				"84 years",
				"86 years"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "84 years"
		},
		{
			"question" : "How is nicknamed the beginning of the universe?",
			"difficult" : "Easy",
			"allAnswers":[
				"Charleroi",
				"Big Bang",
				"Roald Dahl"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "Big Bang"
		},
		{
			"question" : "Who gave the name of the theory of the Big Bang?",
			"difficult" : "Medium",
			"allAnswers":[
				"Fred Hoyle",
				"Edwin Hubble",
				"George Gamow"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "Fred Hoyle"
		},
		{
			"question" : "Who opposed the idea that the Big Bang corresponds with creating the world from nothing?",
			"difficult" : "Hard",
			"allAnswers":[
				"Christians",
				"Catholic priest Georges Lemaître",
				"Atheists"
			],
			"rightAnswer" : "Atheists"
		},
		{
			"question" : "What is the name of the line between the center and the circumference of a circle?",
			"difficult": "Easy",
			"allAnswers": [
				"angle",
				"radius",
				"square"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "radius"
		},
		{
			"question" : "How many moons has the Earth?",
			"difficult": "Medium",
			"allAnswers": [
				"two satellites",
				"a satelitte",
				"three satellites"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "a satelitte"
		},
		{
			"question" : "Approximately what percentage is the oxygen in the air?",
			"difficult": "Hard",
			"allAnswers": [
				"12%",
				"21%",
				"31%"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "21%"
		},
		{
			"question" : "What was the first person who has walked on Luna?",
			"difficult": "Easy",
			"allAnswers": [
				"Yuri Gagarin",
				"Neil Armstrong",
				"Edward H. White"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "Neil Armstrong"
		},
		{
			"question" : "What is the first device which can record and reproduce the sound?",
			"difficult": "Medium",
			"allAnswers": [
				"gramophone",
				"tape recorder",
				"phonograph"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "phonograph"
		},
		{
			"question" : "What was the first person who has walked on Mars?",
			"difficult": "Hard",
			"allAnswers": [
				"Yuri Gagarin",
				"None",
				"Edward H. White"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "None"
		},
		{
			"question" : "What is in the center of the Solar System?",
			"difficult": "Easy",
			"allAnswers": [
				"Earth",
				"Luna",
				"Sun"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "Sun"
		},
		{
			"question" : "On what planet is the largest volcano in the Solar System?",
			"difficult": "Medium",
			"allAnswers": [
				"Terra",
				"Marte",
				"Jupiter"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "Marte"
		},
		{
			"question" : "The last eclipse of the sun when Romania has had as much of the world took place on:",
			"difficult": "Hard",
			"allAnswers": [
				"29 march 2006",
				"15 april 2005",
				"19 may 2009"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "29 march 2006"
		},
		{
			"question" : "What was the capital of the Byzantine Empire?",
			"difficult": "Easy",
			"allAnswers": [
				"Rome",
				"Athens",
				"Constantinople"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "Constantinople"
		},
		{
			"question" : "Care e țara de proveniență a vikingilor?",
			"difficult": "Medium",
			"allAnswers": [
				"Denmark",
				"Ireland",
				"Sweden"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "Denmark"
		},
		{
			"question" : "What is the composition of the diamond?",
			"difficult": "Hard",
			"allAnswers": [
				"Oxygen, hydrogen and manganese",
				"Pure carbon",
				"Nitrogen and silicon"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "Pure carbon"
		},
		{
			"question" : "What is the pressure unit?",
			"difficult": "Easy",
			"allAnswers": [
				"Pascal",
				"Ohm",
				"Watt"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "Pascal"
		},
		{
			"question" : "Which of the following is not a branch of biology?",
			"difficult": "Medium",
			"allAnswers": [
				"Zoology",
				"Virusology",
				"Biochemistry"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "Biochemistry"
		},
		{
			"question" : "What is composed, for the most part, the atmosphere of the planet Venus?",
			"difficult": "Hard",
			"allAnswers": [
				"hydrogen",
				"helium",
				"carbon dioxide gas"
			],
			"rightAnswer": "carbon dioxide gas"
		}
	]

}